Charlie Smith

West Kensington, London

Phone: On request

Email: charlie@blacksmithcomputing.co.uk

Skype: robert.charles.smith

Objective

To deliver value to my clients through quickly adapting to the client's expected practices, and then going beyond by delivering maintainable and automatically tested software that leverages both my increasing experience and industry best practices.

Relevant Work Experience

Man AHL, London, United Kingdom – Quantative Developer (Contract)

October 2017 -

- Technologies: Python 2, Angular 5, numpy, pandas, Oracle, Ansible, Jenkins, Openstack, Linux
- Currently working in the Core Trading Technology team, which is responsible for our in-house trading system, post-signal generation and pre-execution for mainly futures and FX forwards, while providing support to other trading systems that trade the other various instruments.
- Initially contracted as the lead developer on a 2 month greenfield project to build an internal HR tool specced to AHL's requirements, which was delivered on time.

Sabbatical (6 month)

May 2017 – September 2017

LinkedIn: https://nz.linkedin.com/in/chuckus

Github: https://github.com/chuckus

• Travelling between NZ and UK and working on various OSS projects, including chromewhip

Kordia, New Zealand – Software Developer (6 month contract)

November 2016 - April 2017

- Technologies: Python 3, Ember.js, Django, PostgresSQL, Oracle, numpy, pandas, Ansible, Jenkins, Openstack, Linux
- Successfully delivered on a team of 3, the new customer facing portal for providing real-time network data and insights for their internet and cyber securities products, targeted at enterprise IT users. Involved porting of some code and data from a legacy platform running pyramid, Oracle 10g and in-house SOAP services and integrating with existing Microsoft services such as Active Directory.

Map Of Agriculture, New Zealand - Software Developer (6 month contract)

May 2016 – October 2016

- Technologies: Python 3, Go, Django, celery, PostgresSQL, numpy, pandas, PowerBI, AWS, Linux
- With original developers leaving within 1 month of starting, took full responsibility of an in-house data wrangling and financial dashboard platform for corporate farmers. Enhanced and simplified maintenance of the system by moving functionality from celery jobs to go subroutines (apex) running on AWS Lambda

Pensolve, New Zealand - Technical Co-Founder

Aug 2015 - May 2016

- Technologies: Python 3, Ember.js, Flask, celery, PostgresSQL, Docker, Azure, Linux
- Architected and developed a SaaS platform that helps enhance the peer review process of engineering calculation in Microsoft Excel spreadsheets. Our key feature is a complex algorithm that can recognise layout and semantics of spreadsheet calculations and transform into a handwritten format engineers can easily understand.
- Deeply involved in all other business administration and tasks such as sales and marketing.

Kordia, New Zealand - Support Systems Software Developer

Nov 2014 – Aug 2015

- Technologies: Python 2, PostgresSQL, Oracle, Ansible, Linux
- Provide 24/7 on-call support on a roster basis to the operations team on all of the above systems, successfully dealing with urgent issues on mission-critical systems under pressure.
- Improved development cycle efficiency from day one, modernizing the workflow with *Ansible* and *Jenkins*. Within 2 months, development cycle time for one of the pilot projects had shrunk by more than half, by introducting full pipeline continuous integration and deployment system.

Sabbatical (7 month) Feb 2014 – Agust 2017

• Travelling around Latin America

Tait Communications, New Zealand - Design Engineer

Nov 2010 - Feb 2014

- Technologies: Embedded C++, Python 2, Objective-C, Linux
- Supported development and maintenance of Tait's test infrastructure. Specifically, low latency, high transaction simulators using *tornado*, simulating Tait products within a networked environment and the automated RF performance and regression test framework for the TBC base station series, which leveraged various test equipment such as R&S FSUP series spectrum analyzers and E22xx series signal generators.
- Contributed to the development using C++ on OSI Layer 2 and 3 of the P25 Phase 2 communications standard, targeting the TI DaVinci platform within the Tait TB9400 series base station.
- Responsible for the maintenance, enhancement and support of the, which I had only 2 weeks to absorb the working knowledge from the sole author and maintainer who then left the company.
- Successfully developed a working prototype for a situational awareness application sent to the US during the APCO 2013 convention in the US to prototype a disaster response solution with international partners.
- Starting as a Junior Design Engineer during a summer internship, I became a graduate after finishing
 university and then after a year, won an internal award for excellence in junior engineering which led to an
 early promotion to intermediate level, attributed to sustained effort and tangible successes in my areas of
 responsibility.
- Mentored two summer students to provide support for the above projects.

Education

Scalable Machine Learning with certificate, Online edX course run by BerkeleyX Functional Programming Principles in Scala

August 2015 Nov 2013

Online Coursera course run by École Polytechnique Fedérale De Lausanne

Startup Engineering, Online Coursera course run by Stanford University

Sep 2013

Bachelor of Engineering with Honours in Electrical and Electronic Engineering (2nd class, 1st division) University of Canterbury, Christchurch, New Zealand

Feb 2008 – Nov 2011

Extra Curricular Activities

- **Calisthenics** Starting 3 months ago after wanting a change from weight lifting.
- **Ukulele** Started as an alternative to Guitar so that I could take an ukulele while traveling.
- **Spanish** Spent 5 weeks learning Spanish in Nicaragua and Guatemala and regularly maintain my knowledge.

Referees

Referees can be provided upon request